A Guide to the Papers of the Low Moor Iron Company
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Records
  - Low Moor Iron Co. Coal Dept. - correspondence from E. M. Cabell to S. G. Cargill, 1905 -1906 (Box Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L-W", incl. Lambert Hoisting Engine Co., David Lamond - Contracting Engineer, Warren Webster Co., Low Moor, 1895 -1906 (Box Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L", incl. Henry W. Lords, Link Beit Engineering Co., Levy, Pricex Co., J. M. Lickiter, 1895 -1899 (Box Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S", incl. Sears Roebuck & Co., O. W. Shipman Co. - Coal, Chas Sentz, Sherwin Williams Co., The Sheet Metal Mfg. Co., Simmons Hardware, Simpson Realtor, Skillin & Richards Mfg. Co., 1902 -1904; (3 folders) (Box Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence from Smith Courtney Co., 1902 -1904 (Box Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S", incl. Smokeless Fuel Co., H. M. Swift, 1902 -1906; (2 folders) (Box Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", (2 parts) incl. Carnegie Steel Co., Chapman Iron Co., Chicago Pneumatic Tool Co., C. L. Cleek, Cincinnati Iron Store Co., Carey Machinery, Cambria Steel Co., Cameron Steam Pump Works, 1904 -1905 (Box Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. McAllister & Bell, Manhattan Rubber Co., May Shoes, The MacDonald Co., 1901 (Box Box 48)
  - Thomas A. Mack & Co., 1902 -1903; (5 folders) (Box Box 48)
  - Dalton Nash & Co., 1906 -1907; (3 folders) (Box Box 48)
  - Walter Wallingford & Co. and Dalton Nash & Co., 1906 -1907 (Box Box 48)
  - Furnace equipment lists, 1919 (Box Box 49)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. intra-company correspondence, 1900 -1902; (6 folders) (Box Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. Matthew Addy Co., Manufacturers Record, Manhasset Coal Co., R. G. Miller - Sales Mgr., Massen Coal Co., 1920 -1921; (2 folders) (Box Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "N", incl. National Coal Assoc., Navy Dept, National Trading Co., New York Coal Export Co., 1920 -1921 (Box Box 49)
  - Freight rates from Low Moor, 1917 -1919 (Box Box 49)
  - Prices of coal, coke, etc., 1918 (Box Box 49)
  - National Coal Assoc. and National Audit Co., 1919 (Box Box 49)
  - G. W. Layman - Attorney-at-Law, 1916 (Box Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D", incl. Deloitte, Pender, Griffiths, 1917 (Box Box 49)
  - Quarry reports from Supt, 1917 -1918 (Box Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B", incl. U. S. Geological Survey, Bothwell Co., Bingham Co., 1893 -1899 (Box Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "W", incl. Woodrow Ruder Co., Worthington Co., Woodward & Iron Co., T. W. Wood & Sons, Walter Wood Mowing & Reaping Co., Wood Brown & Co., Wythe Lead & Zinc Co., A. F. Withrow Lumber Co., Robert Witherill & Co., James Witherow & Co., Woodcock Iron Works, Woolson Spice Co., A. & C. Wright Co., Winifred Coal Co., Winona Wagon Co., Samuel Winston & Co., Winchester New Rival, 1891 -1900; (4 folders) (Box Box 50)
  - E. H. Wilson Co., 1895 -1900; (2 folders) (Box Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Y", incl. Thomas Yager, Youngstown Bosh Plate Co., York Dynamite Co., 1895 -1899 (Box Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "Z", incl. John Zimmerman, August Zaubitz-Hotblast Pyrometers, 1895 -1899 (Box Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B", incl. Brown Coal Co., Boone Smokeless Coal Co., W. A. Barrows - Mgr. Goshern Furnace Corp., 1920 -1921 (Box Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", incl. Chamber of Commerce - U. S., Continental Iron & Steel Co., W. E. Circle, Crenshaw Coal Co., Charles Catlet, Clement K. Quinn & Co., General Chemical Co., Cleveland Engineering Agency, Carson & Co., Mr. Chandler - Report from Rochester, Hoffmann Iron & Steel, Cleveland Cliffs Co., 1919 -1921; (2 folders) (Box Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D", incl. report on financial situation of Low Moor by H. Dalton - treasurer, Dupont Co., Dixie Lumber Co., Delano Coal Co., John C. Dillion, 1920 -1921 (Box Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "O", incl. Old Dominion Coal & Coke Assoc., Meeting of Operators Assoc. - Low Moor - to discuss business conditions, 1920 -1921 (Box Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "N-P", incl. Pulaski Iron Co., Pioneer Coal & Coke Co., Pacific Mail Steamship Co., Navy Department - order for Low Moor, Poors Publishing Co., 1920 -1921 (Box Box 51)
  - Walter Wallingford (successors to Thomas A. Mack) and Thomas A. Mack, 1896 -1905; (2 folders) (Box Box 51)
  - Thomas A. Mack - orders and correspondence, 1896 -1897; (4 folders) (Box Box 51)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. - intra-company correspondence, 1898 -1899 (Box Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L", 1896 -1898 (Box Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "V", incl. Vulcan Iron Works Co., Virginia Pipe & Foundry Co., Virginia Iron, Coal & Coke Co., Virginia Iron & Railway Co., Virginia Nail & Iron Works Co., Vacuum Oil Co., Virginia Bridge & Iron Co., 1894 -1906 (Box Box 52)
  - C. & O. Coal & Coke Co. - receipts and correspondence, 1904 July -Sept.; (2 folders) (Box Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", incl. Chapman Iron & Coal Co., C. & O. Coke Co., Chicago Pneumatic Tool Co., Cincinnati Pump Co., Cincinnati Iron Store Co., Chicago Housewrecking Co., 1904 (Box Box 52)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. - intra-company correspondence, 1895 -1899; (5 folders) (Box Box 52A)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H", incl. Heywood Bros. & Co., Heyl & Patterson, D. Y. Huddlestun, Home Brown & Co., H. C. Horton & Co., John A. Homer & Co., E. I. Horsman, J. W. Hopkins - Agent, New River & Kanawha Railroad, Peter Henderson & Co., The Hendrick Manufacturing Co., Hendricks Munro & Co., Raydock Bros. Carriage Co., Hazard Manufacturing Co., P. Heiskell Smith, Heim Belting Co., Henry Heile & Sons, Heine Safety Boiler Co., Hechinger Bros. & Co., Thomas Henderson & Son, Dickinson Manufacturing Co., Hercules Powder Co., Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad - Hendrix, Hazard Powder Co., R. H. Hayden, Dr. P. Harold Hayes, M. C. Henley, Hench & Dromgold, C. M. Henderson & Co., The High Carbon Coal Co., Hesser Milton, C. W. Hunt & Co. - illustration, E. M. Hunter, H. Hunter, Joseph L. Hunter, Allen Anti-Rust, F. K. Hurxthal, Humphreys, Stewart & Co., John E. Hurst & Co., Hyde Bros. & Co. - one blueprint, Percy R. Hynson Co., J. W. Hopkins - Coal Agent, C. I. Hubbard Co., 1892 -1908; (6 folders) (Box Box 53)
  - Hercules Powder Manufacturing Co. correspondence, 1894 -1899 (Box Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "W", incl. J. W. Warren, Warren Foundry & Machine, A. E. White, White Star Mills, William Washington, Frank Watson, A. Whitney & Sons, R. S. Whitten, The Weir Frog Co., The W. E. Fugo Co., William Sweet - Dept. of the Census, Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Co., Western Pig Iron Assoc., Western Union Telegraph, Wells Machine Works, T. F. Welch, Westinghouse Church & Kerr Co., The Watt Mining Car Wheel Co., Whitehurst & Smith, N. C. Watts, Washington Carbon Co., Watkins Cottnell Co., C. N. Waterman PHC, Watkins Caldwell & Rinehart, W. & S. Hydroelectric Machine Works, Washington Telephone Co., John Wesley, Westfork Coal & Coke Co., Town Clerk - West, Wayne Hardware Co., Everett Waddey Co., N. C. Wegg, Weather Flags - U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, Joseph Wharton, Weeks Scale Works, Weeks - Dept. of the Interior, Dr. N. Wayt & Bros., Weimar Machine Works, Warren Webster Co., Western Electric Co., C. C. Walker - Supt transportation - Ohio Railroad, John B. Watson, Walter Wallingford & Co., Walker Carrol Adams, J. B. Westbrook Foundry, West Virginia Fire Clay Co., West Virginia Pulp & Paper Co., Westover Paper Co., Wellman Seaver Morgan Co., 1891 -1905; (6 folders) (Box Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H", incl. J. W. Hopkins - Agent C. & O. Railroad, Hoopes & Tonsend Co., Howard & Morse, John Holland Gold Pen Co., Howe Scales, Howard & Davis, Lewis Hubbard, A. E. Huddleston, Hoppes Manufacturing Co., John A. Homer Co., U. T. Hungerford Brass & Copper Co., The Huber Manufacturing Co., L. W. Hunt Co., Joseph L. Hunter - Mechanical Engineer, Frank A. Hutson, Percy R. Hynson, Hyde Bros. & Co., Hinton Market Co., Hilles & Jones Co., George B. Hiss Oil & Supply Co., Hickman Williams & Co., O. Hileman, W. C. Hundley, Cal Hirsch, J. D. Hippard, Lamokin, Hockensmith Wheel Co., J. J. Hobbs - Clerk, Henry Hobbs, John L. Hogan Co., George A. Hogg Co., Plewes & Hodges Co., 1900 -1904; (8 folders) (Box Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A", incl. Ashland Fire Brick Co., American Cart Foundry Co., American Cereal Co., American Frog & Switch Co., American Cotton Oil Co., 1903 (Box Box 54)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. correspondence - Treasurer Low to H. G. Merry discussing financial situation of Low Moor, 1892 -1899; (3 folders) (Box Box 54)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. correspondence - Lyman to Merry, 1897 -1902 (Box Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L", incl. Lidgerwood Manufacturing Co. illustration of a machine, Chas L. Lemon, C. B. Leckey, Lane Bros. Co., David Lamond - contracting engineer, 1899 (Box Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "K", incl. Kanawha Fuel Co., Kayser & Allman, Kanawha Gazette, T. D. Kauffel, D. S. Cook, Kroger, Redway & Co., A. Lee Knowles, Garner D. Kline, Michael Kiuligan, Kroger Coal & Coke, Albert Krimmert, Knowles Steam Pump Works, Kirchoff - Iron Age, Arthur Kirk & Son, H. W. Knight & Son, The King Bridge Co., The Kilbourne & Jacobs Manufacturing Co., E. A. Kinsey & Co., E. Keeley & Co., Walter Kennedy Egr., Kellegg Switchboard Supply Co., Kennedy & Miller, King Folding Canvas Boat Co., 1891 -1904; (6 folders) (Box Box 55)
  - E. Keeler Co., 1895 -1899 (Box Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "K-L", incl Charles L. Lemon, E. A. Kinsey, Kingsland & Douglas Manufacturing Co., 1895 -1897 (Box Box 55)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. - correspondence and miscellaneous "K", incl. Kentucky Firebrick Co., Kerr Gordon & Co., Keystone Mutual Fire Insurance Co., 1895 -1904 (Box Box 55)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. - intra-company correspondence, Gast to E. C. Means, 1904; (5 folders) (Box Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A", incl. Ashland Steel Co., American Water Softener Co., Adams Bros.-Paynes Co., George E. Afflect, Allegheny Pin & Bracket Co., Allegheny Milling Co., Allegheny Ore & Iron Co., American Pig Iron Co., American Locomotive Co., Allis Chamlers Co., The Alcatraz Co., Allegheny Iron & Steel, Akron Cultivator Co., American Iron & Steel Assoc., American Cart Foundry Co., American Pig Iron Storage Co., American Foundry man's Assoc., Ashland Firebrick Co., Armour & Co., Armstrong Bros. Co., Austin Powder Co., C. W. Arny & Sons, American Steel & Wire Co., American Car Ore Co., The Aeolian Co., American Brazing Co., American Tool Works Co., 1901 -1905; (9 folders) (Box Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "R", incl. Rich Patch survey of possible Low Moor purchase, R. W. Reid, Remington Standard Co., Reeves Bros., A. Raymond & Co., Rand Drill Co., Richmond Standard Spike & Iron Co., Richard Locomotive, 1891 -1895; (3 folders) (Box Box 56)
  - Dalton Nash & Co. incl. E. I. Dupont & Co., 1904 -1905; (10 folders) (Box Box 57)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "D", incl. H. R. Kurkee Pig Iron Commission, F. A. Dupuy, Dupont Co., Dixon Crucible Co., Joe Dixon, Dickinson Firebrick Co., Dalton Nash & Co., Davis Firebrick Co., 1904 -1905; (3 folders) (Box Box 57)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "O", incl. Oriental Power Mills, F. H. Odiorne & Co., Otis Elevator Co., Old Dominion Nail Works, Oil City Boiler Works, Ohio Paint & Varnish Co., Oglebay Norton & Co., Olive Foundry & Machine Co., 1901 -1904; (2 folders) (Box Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L", incl. Longacre Colliery Co., Lynchburg Plow Co., Loewenstein & Sons, Low Moor Iron Co. - office of the Treasurer, C. & O. Railroad Co. vs John Tucker, Frank Lyman to Robert Parrish, Lagonda Mfg Co., Laidlow-Dunn-Gordon, Lidgerwood Mfg. Co., Lewisburg Milling, Leonard & Ellis, R. N. Gaw & Son, Lane Bros. Co., 1901 -1902; (3 folders) (Box Box 58)
  - C. G. Blake & Co., 1899 -1900 (Box Box 58)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. - office of the Treasurer, 1901 -1902; (2 folders) (Box Box 58)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "G", incl. General Electric Co., Glamorgan Pipe & Foundry Co., Grice, Mgr of Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad, Garlock, Garry Iron & Steel Co., Gasoline Rock Drill Co., Joseph Gregg, The Goheen Manufacturing Co., B. F. Goodrich Co., The Grasselli Chemical Co., 1904 -1906; (4 folders) (Box Box 59)
  - Glamorgan Pipe & Foundry Co., 1904 -1906 (Box Box 59)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L", incl. Lynchburg Pipe & Foundry Co., Low Moor Iron Co. - intra-company correspondence, 1901; (2 folders) (Box Box 59)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. - intra-company correspondence: Gast to Means, Cabell to Cargill, Cabell to Means, 1905; (3 folders) (Box Box 60)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. - intra-company correspondence and miscellaneous correspondence "W", incl. Western Union Telegraph, E. H. Wilson Co., 1889 -1904 (Box Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "E, T, A, M, V, G", incl. Goodrich Co., Egan Co., Tredegar Co., American Foote Powder, Miller School of Albemarle, American Pig Iron Assoc., 1888 -1889 (Box Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S, T, V, B, M", 1889 (Box Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "O, P, R", incl. E. Pratt & Bros., William Renton, Ronceverte Foundry Co., R. B. Rose, 1889 (Box Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "L, M, P", incl. McIntosh Hemphrill & Co., Warner Moore, Pratt & Sons, 1888 -1889 (Box Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H, K, I", incl. S. H. Hawes, Huddlestun, Ilseu, Doubleday & Co., Hoen lithographer, 1889 -1900 (Box Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "E, G, F", incl. Ono Gourlie & Co., Ellison & Austin, Eatile & Co., Fay & Co., Gaines & Glover - Agents, 1889 -1902 (Box Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "B", incl. The Banner Feed Co., Baltimore Rubber Co., Baldwin Locomotive Works, The Baker Glass Co., Earle C. Bacon, The Baughman Stationery Co., Barton, Wilmer, Ambler & Stewart, G. & A. Bargamin Co., JHC Barr, Barke-Jennings Hardware Co., Bessemer Coke Co., Best Manufacturing Co., The W. Bingham Co., C. G. Blake Co., R. L. Barnes Co., Frances Beidler & Co., Belfont Iron Works Co., Bertolette Machinery Agency, Berlin Construction Co., Blacken, Blume, 1894 -1903; (5 folders) (Box Box 61A)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A", incl. Edward Allis Co., Allegheny Steel Co., William Allen, 1896 -1899 (Box Box 61A)
  - C. G. Blake & Co., 1901 -1902; (2 folders) (Box Box 61A)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A", incl. The Argand Refining Co., Arbuckle Co., Armour Co., Atlantic Dynamite Co. Austin Nicholls Co., William Anderson, Andrew Andrews - Tredegar Iron Works, A. O. Fay, President Miami Powder Co., Acme Mineral Ore Co., Akron Cultivator Co., Albrights Son & Co., 1895 -1899; (5 folders) (Box Box 61B)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "American", incl. American Champion Plaster Co., American Electric Telephone Co., American Cereal Co., American Iron & Steel Assoc., 1895 -1899 (Box Box 61B)
  - C. & O. Railroad Co. from G. T. Wickes, 1906 -1907 (Box Box 62)
  - Railroad Construction from G. T. Wickes, 1906 -1907 (Box Box 62)
  - Wickes to Low Moor on equipment, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Rinehart & Reynolds monthly estimates to Wickes, 1906 -1907 (Box Box 62)
  - Claims from G. T. Wickes, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Carts from G. T. Wickes, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Coke from G. T. Wickes, 1905 -1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Coke drawing from G. T. Wickes, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Cement from G. T. Wickes, 1906 -1907 (Box Box 62)
  - Rail from G. T. Wickes, 1905 -1907 (Box Box 62)
  - Railroad rates from G. T. Wickes, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Crops: damage, claims, putting out, etc. from G. T. Wickes, 1906 -1907 (Box Box 62)
  - Country roads from G. T. Wickes, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Costs from G. T. Wickes, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Cars from G. T. Wickes, 1907 (Box Box 62)
  - Rents from G. T. Wickes, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Roofing from G. T. Wickes, 1906 (Box Box 62)
  - Low Moor Iron Co. intra-company correspondence, incl. Fenwick Mines transportation billing, employing labor, transportation, right of way through property, shortage of cement at Covington, shortage of cars at Fenwick, Condition of country (1905), general supplies, lumber, sand, firebrick orders, concrete mixers, expense account, taking care of cement labor problems, ordering material, prices on material, 1905 -1907; (9 folders) (Box Box 62A)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "S", incl. The Shaw Walker Co., S. B. Sexton & Son, J. B. Shannon & Sons, Seaboard Steel Co., Smith Courtney Co., J. S. Sipp - Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad, Stoss Sheffield Steel & Iron Co., Howard Siddel, Simmons Hardware Co., Sherwin Williams Co., Thomas J. Shyrock & Co., Smokeless Fuel Co., Isaac A. Sheppard & Co., Smith & Snead, Smith Premier Typewriter, O. B. Smith, S. C. Higgens - Traffic Mgr. Coal Operations Assoc., 1898 -1922; (6 folders) (Box Box 63)
  - Robert Parrish - Attorney-at-Law Low Moor business legal matters, 1901 -1902; (2 folders) (Box Box 63)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "P", incl. Patterson Tool & Dye Co., Peaslee-Gaubbert Co., J. C. Patton & Co., Patterson Tool & Supply Co., Parker - Statistician for the U.S. Geological Survey, Pennsylvania Steel Co., Pettinos Brother, Phoenix Oil Co., Pierce, Butler and Pierce; Price - Engineer of the Chesapeake & Ohio Railway Co., Robert L. Parrish Attorney-at-Law, Pierce & Akers Co., Pioneer Junk Co., Pirklen & Page, William B. Pollock & Co., Princess Furnace, Pratt & Zetchworth Co., Poulteror & Co. - machinery, Powers & Anderson, Puchta Pund & Co., Leo McDaniel, The Pullman Co., Queen & Co., Palmer & Fuller Co., 1900 -1902; (6 folders) (Box Box 63)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "G", incl. Joseph Gregg - grain shipper, F. M. Greenough & Co., Walter Graham - Iron & Steel, Grasselli Chemical Co., Frank Graham - Iron & Steel, Greensborough Lumber Co., A. A. Griffing Iron Co., J. W. Guinn & Co., General Electric Co., Georgia Lumber Co., William Gibbs, The Garry Iron & Steel Co., Goodman Manufacturing Co., B. F. Goodrich Co., Goheen Manufacturing Co., Goff, Homer & Co. Ltd., Glamorgan Iron & Pipe Co., Gregg Ervin & Co., W. H. Gordon Co., Frank C. Grote & Co., John N. Gordon, The Gaulen Mountain Coal Co., Graichin Glove Co., Gates Iron Works, Gooch Rinehart & Co., Supt - Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad, James Goldmark, Gaines & Glover - Agents, Garlock Packing Co., Garvin Machine Co., 1891 -1904; (12 folders) (Box Box 64)
  - Glamorgan Pipe & Foundry Co., 1902 -1903 (Box Box 64)
  - Thomas A. Mack & Co. - orders, 1901 -1902; (5 folders) (Box Box 65)
  - Thomas A. Mack & Co., and Walter Wallingford & Co. (successors to Thomas A. Mack & Co.) - orders, 1902 -1906; (2 folders) (Box Box 65)
  - Walter Wallingford & Co. - orders, 1905 -1906; (6 folders) (Box Box 66)
  - Thomas A. Mack & Co. - orders, 1903; (4 folders) (Box Box 66)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", incl. Clifton Iron Co., Climax Refining Co., Climax Powder Co., Carnegie Steel Co., Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad, W. H. Carter Contractors, Cambria Iron Co., 1897 -1906; (2 folders) (Box Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H", incl. Hartranft Cement Co., Hendrick Manufacturing Co., Hercules Powder Co., 1903 -1906; (2 folders) (Box Box 67)
  - Chesapeake & Ohio Railway, 1897; (2 folders) (Box Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "N", incl. National Lead Co., Natural Science Assoc., National Electric Co., Newport News Shipping & Drydock Co., National Biscuit Co., New River & Kanawha Coal & Coke Co., National Bank of Commerce, National Drill & Manufacturing Co., National Paint & Varnish Co., 1902 -1904; (2 folders) (Box Box 68)
  - New River & Kanawha Coal Co., 1902 -1903 (Box Box 68)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H, N", incl. B. Nicoll & Co., Harbison-Walker Manufacturing Co., Harbison & Gathwright, Cranes Nest Coal & Coke Co., H. Hardaway - Accountant, R. F. Harris & Co., 1900 -1905 (Box Box 68)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C, H.", incl. Payne & Hamilton - Attorneys-at-Law, Covington Machine Co., Win & Hallam, 1904 -1906 (Box Box 68)
  - M. A. Hanna & Co. - orders, 1904 -1906 (Box Box 68)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H, S", incl. Harrison Boiler works, Sattler Manufacturing Co., W. G. Hartranft Cement Co., Harrington & King Perforating Co., R. F. Harris, Val Duttenfore & Sons Co., 1902 -1906 (Box Box 68)
  - Kay Moor Mines intra-company correspondence, 1903 July -1904 Feb.; (4 folders) (Box Box 68A)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. McKiernan Drill Co., McDowell & Co., McLanahan-Stone Machine Co., Peter McLaren, Meehan Builert Construction Co., McNeal Pipe & Foundry Co., Sheriff Machinery Co., Means & Kuiton Iron Works, 1901 -1904; (3 folders) (Box Box 68A)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "W", incl. Woodward Iron Co., Woodward & Son Lumber, Henry Worthington Pumping Engine, T. B. Wood - Engineer, Wickes writing to Cargill, E. B. Willard & Co., Willson Aluminum Co., Wileu & Russell Manufacturing Co., Wickes Brother, E. H. Wilson & Co., J. F. Winslow & Co., Frank W. Winner & Sons, George E. Witt Shoe Co., J. T. Wing & Co., L. Wolf & Bro. - Scrap Iron, Frank Woodmansee - Inks, T. W. Wood & Sons, Morris Woodhull, T. L. Woodruft Co., Western Electric Co., George Whitcomb Co., The Woodrow Stationery Printing Co., 1900 -1906; (5 folders) (Box Box 69)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "W, Y", incl Youngstown Iron & Steel Roofing Co., Walter & Zenicker Supply Co., Watertown Engine Co., Yawman & Erbell Manufacturing Co., Yale & Towne Manufacturing Co., 1900 -1906 (Box Box 69)
  - Hunter B. Frischkorn - Railway, Machinists, Miners & Mill, 1906 (Box Box 69)
  - Smith Courtney Co.- correspondence, quotations, orders, 1898 -1902; (3 folders) (Box Box 70)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "M", incl. Warner-Moore & Co., Moore Lime Co., Chas Moore Oil Co., Masurite Explosive Co., Maryland Steel Co., Mitchell Lumber Co., Missouri Belting Co., William P. Miller Co., Miller Supply Co., H. J. Morris - Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad, Morris Wheeler & Co., Mosler Safe Co., Marion Steam Shovel Co., Magnolia Metal Co., David Miller, H. Erskine Miller - Grocer, George Miles - Timber, A. E. Muers & Bro. - Lifts, The Mount Carbon Co. - Foundry, Furnace, & Coke, 1900 -1902; (4 folders) (Box Box 70)
  - Orders from Miller Supply Co., 1900 -1902; (3 folders) (Box Box 70)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H, M, W, T", incl. Weir Frog Co., Tuler Engine Co., Goodrich Rubber, Staunton Development Co., 1891 -1906 (Box Box 71)
  - Hunter B. Frischkorn, 1904 -1905 (Box Box 71)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "F", incl. Harry B. Flood - U.S. House of Representatives, Fidelity Casualty Co. Forster - Waterbury & Co. - Iron, Fostoria Glass, Fenton - Sales Agent, The Fairbanks Co., Walter B. Frischkorn - Supplies, Levi Farmer & Son - Steam Boilers, Harry Fraizer Consulting Engineer, Farmers Supply Co., 1904 -1906; (2 folders) (Box Box 71)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "T", incl. Thurmond Coal Co., Tredegar Iron Works, Erskine Miller - President of Thurmond Coal Co., New River Coal Co., 1889 -1894; (2 folders) (Box Box 71)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "H, G, T, W, S" incl. Thomas Publishing Co., Tredegar Iron Works, Taws & Hartman, Gordon Steam Pump Co., Southern Bell, Scioto Valley Grain Co., 1889 -1892 (Box Box 71)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C", incl. Hotel Cumberland, Corrigan, McRinney Co., Covington Machine Co., Consumers Fuel Co., Commonwealth of Virginia Census & Tax, 1905 -1906 (Box Box 72)
  - Thomas A. Mack & Co. - letters and correspondence, 1902 March -April; (3 folders) (Box Box 72)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "A, W" correspondence, 1904 -1905 (Box Box 72)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence "C, K", incl. John Cronis & Co. - Paints, Crown Oil & Wax Co., Crescent Supply Co., Covington Machine Co., 1905 Jan. -1906 Feb. (Box Box 72)